journal.com.ph 2003-06-18

# Journal Online

JOURNAL ONLINE INTERACTIVE PRIVACY POLICY 

This privacy statement discloses the privacy practices for www.journal.com.ph. 

It is the Journal Interactive's continuing goal to build users' trust and confidence in the Internet by promoting the use of fair information practices. Because this website wants to demonstrate its commitment to your privacy, it has agreed to disclose its information and user privacy practices. 

This website has agreed to notify you of: 

What personally identifiable information of yours or third party personal identification is collected from you through the website 

The organization collecting the information 

How the information is used 

With whom the information may be shared 

What choices are available to you regarding collection, use and distribution of the information 

How you can correct any inaccuracies in the information. 

If you feel that this company is not abiding by its posted privacy policy, contact feedback@journal.com.ph 

Information collection and use 

The Journal Interactive is the sole owner of the information collected on this site. We will not sell, share or rent this information to others in ways different from what is disclosed in this statement. The Journal Interactive collects information from our users at several different points on our website. 

This site, Journal Interactive, uses the services of Engage for the serving and/or targeting of ads, promotions and other marketing messages. To do this, Engage collects anonymous data through the use of cookies. To learn more about Engage, including your ability to opt out of the Engage system, go to http://www.engage.com/privacy. 

Online surveys and promos 

When the Journal Interactive holds surveys or promos, users are sometimes required to give their contact information (such as name and e-mail address). This information is used to contact the user about the services on our site for which they have expressed interest or to inform them if they have won in a certain contest or promo. It is optional for the user to provide demographic information (such as income level and gender) and unique identifiers (such as social security number or driver's license number). 

E-mail services 

The Journal Interactive offers various e-mail services. We require information from the user in order for him or her to avail of such free services. This information is used only as contact information and reference. It is optional for the user to provide demographic information (such as income level and gender) and unique identifiers (such as social security number or driver's license number), but encouraged so we can provide a more personalized experience regarding our e-mail services. 

Cookies 

The Journal Interactive itself does not employ cookies at the moment. A cookie is a piece of data stored on the user's hard drive containing information about the user. However, since cookies can enable websites to track and target the interests of its users to enhance the experience on the site, we may in the future make use of cookies. 

Some of our business partners use cookies on our site (for example, advertisers). However, we have no access to or control over these cookies. 

Log Files 

We use IP addresses to analyze trends, administer the site, track user's movement and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. IP addresses are not linked to personally identifiable information. 

Sharing 

We will share aggregated demographic information with our partners and advertisers. This is not linked to any personal information that can identify any individual person. 

We partner with other parties to provide specific services. When the user signs up for these services, we may be required to share names, or other contact information that is absolutely necessary for the third party to provide these services. 

These parties are not allowed to use personally identifiable information except for the purpose of providing these services. 

Links 

This website contains links to other sites. Please be aware that the Journal Interactive is not responsible for the privacy practices of other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every website that collects personally identifiable information. Read our LINK POLICY. 

Notification of changes 

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on our homepage so our users are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it and under circumstances, if any, we disclose it. If at any point we decide to use personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time it was collected, we will notify users by e-mail. Users will have a choice as to whether or not we use their information in this different manner. We will use information in accordance with the privacy policy under which the information was collected.
